

Mobile: 0450122324
Email: sannan.ijaz@gmail.com
Profile: linkedin.com/in/sannanijaz/

Git: https://github.com/Sannan-Ijaz/Sannan

Over 4 years of experience in IT Consulting Role with strong writing skills, experience in solving issues, maximising growth, improving business performance and building client relationships across all levels of an organization. Demonstrated proficiency in process improvement, automation, and AGILE Project Delivery. Passionate about advancing career in software engineering. Just completed a three month boot camp at General Assembly, having written softwares in JS, HTML, CSS, and React.

Experience

General Assembly

Software Engineering | Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- •Tic Tac Go using JS, CSS, HTML.
- A Basic CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) inventory management application for a small business. Built using JS, PostgreSQL, Node JS, and CSS.
- Restaurant Finder using Google API, which can help a user to find the restaurants near them.

Telstra

Networks Technical Analyst | Jan 2020 - Sep 2020

- Assisting in finding pragmatic, cost effective solutions to identify security and risk issues.
- Providing aggravated risk oversight for the high impact areas of IT services for core components of IT risk mitigation, governance and measurement and reporting activities.
- Actively engaging in end to end risk mediation planning, resolution and monitoring activities, including Technology continuity

IBM (International Business Machines) | Melbourne, Australia

Integrated Services Manager | March 2019 - Dec 2020

- •Worked across Service Providers (IBM + Third Party) to deliver managed services to one of IBM's largest retail client.
- Lead ISM Process awareness and provided education to offshore teams to ensure efficient delivery.
- Facilitated continual service improvement of multiple accounts.

Business Analyst | Jun 2017 - March 2019

- Offshored major part of BAU activities while maintaining onshore quality checks as part of Multi-Million dollar transformation project.
- Lead the Account team into Overhaul and Analysis of the Legacy Systems deployed by the account team, designed a proposal for IBM, which got approved and led to increase in efficiency by 30%.
- Established Recon Systems in tools for the client which has showed consistent savings of 70K AUD average every quarter.

Associate Portfolio Director | Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

- •Managed an enterprise wide strategy and performance of portfolios for synergy across multiple portfolios i.e. Retail, Energy, and Insurance aligned with IBM business strategy.
- Part of team of Process Improvement Initiative to standardise the reports for every client, which reduced time by 6 FTEs improving the process efficiency of the business unit by 40%..

MYITHub | Melbourne, Australia | Business Analyst | Oct 2016 - Dec 2017

- Consulting corporate clients in IT product management i.e. Mobile Phone integration, Unified Messaging, Industrial Gateways, and VOIP.
- Software and Products Documentation.
- Purchase and Procurement of inventories from vendors with focus on efficiency amplification.

Education

General Assembly (Software Engineering Immersive)

12 week Bootcamp deep diving into software engineering Stack: JS, Ruby, Node, React, HTML, CSS

Sep'20 - Dec'20

University of Melbourne

Masters in Engineering Management

Jan'14 - Dec'15

Track: Project Management & Entrepreneurship

Lahore University of Management Sciences, Pakistan B.S Electrical Engineering

Mar'09 –May'14

Concentration: Embedded Electronics | Minor: Economics & Finance

Other Experiences

Victoria SSL Open Pennant | Melbourne University | Jan 2018 - Ongoing

- For maintaining a healthy work-life balance, I play squash regularly representing Melbourne University Squash Club.
- Winner of the Winter SSL Open Tournament Victoria 2018.